Guide to the Rebecca Spring Papers, ca. 1830-1900
Department of Special Collections
- Incoming correspondence (including selected names mentioned in letters).
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Feb. 17, [n.y.].Writes about her 50th wedding anniversary and her book. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Stevens, Aaron Dwight. See Letcher, John; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 120, 125, 137-140, 142-160, 162-169, 171. R. Spring has copied some of Stevens' letters, whole or in part, in her typescript, dated Dec. 2, 1859(p. 138); Dec. 31, [1859](p. 139); [n.d.](p. 140); Dec. 17, [1859](p. 140); Dec. 31, 1859(pp. 142-143); [n.d.](p. 144); Jan. 31, 1860(p. 145); [n.d.](p. 146); March 13, 1860(p. 146).
  - Stevens, H.E. Empty envelope. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Stoddard, [?]. See Clemens, Samuel Langhorne.
  - Sumner, Charles. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 80, 88.
  - Thom, William. 2 ALS, [both letters are damaged, no signature on the second letter], 2 pp., Oct. 9, [n.y.];Friday noon, [n.y].A third letter by Eliza Fox. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Thursday, [n.y.]. The Weaver Poet. Gave Rebecca Spring & Mary Fuller each a table cloth of his own knitting. See also R. Spring's typescript, p. 47. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Thompson, George. 3 ALS, 8 pp., Feb. 26, 1835; July 12, 1865; Nov. 27, 1865.Thompson was an English reformer and abolitionist who came to the U.S. at the request of anti-slavery societies to lecture in 1834.His efforts led to the formation of many new anti-slavery groups, but he also encountered great protest and violent mobs and had to escape for fear of his life in Boston in 1835. The first letter here, written from Boston, is about his lecture tour and the problems he was encountering. The other two letters are written from Buffalo and Boston when Thompson returned in 1865,and they also concern his activities. See also R. Spring's typescript, p. 86. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Thompson, Ruth Brown. 1 ALS, 3 pp., April 27, 1898.Daughter of John Brown. (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Thoreau, Henry David. See Emerson, Ralph Waldo.
  - [UNK]
  - Trollope, Mrs. See Fuller, Margaret.
  - Walpole, Horace. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 56.
  - Washington, Brooker T. 1 TNS, 1 p., April 22, 1902. (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Washington, George. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 106, 174; and D. Invitations.
  - Watts, Alfred. 1 ALS, 4 pp., April 13, 1860. (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Weld, Theodore Dwight and Angelina Grimke Weld. See Bodichon, Barbara; Brown, Henry Kirke; Child, Lydia Maria; Garrison, William Lloyd; Griffith, Mattie; for Theodore Weld, see also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 84, 86, 161, 171.
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf. 1 ALS, 1 p., May [?] 5, 1865 [?].See also R. Spring's ts., pp. 167-168 (typed copy of a letter by Whittier, dated 8th Mo. [= Aug.?] 11th [1860]),178-180. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Whittredge, W. 1 ALS, 2 pp., [n.d.].Landscape painter. (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Wilkinson, Dr. James John Garth. 1 AL [letter severely damaged, no signature], 3 pp., [n.d.].Very famous English physician. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Winter, William. 1 ALS, 1 p., April 23, 1904.Best-known American dramatic critic. Author of `Mary of Magdala.' Poet. (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Wordsworth, William. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 25-31 [poem Lines To My Sister on pp. 26-27], 56.
  - Wulff, Henriette. 5 ALS, 17 pp., Sept. 12, 1854; May 1, 1855; March 10, 1856; June 27, 1856; March 12, 1858.Empty envelope from Hans Christian Anderson. Daughter of Admiral Wulff. Friend of Hans Christian Anderson. See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 99-101. (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Manuscripts
  - Spring, Rebecca. 180 pages of the corrected typescript of A Book of Remembrance., with parts of an uncorrected copy of the typescript; n.d.,but circa 1900.Pages 8-11, 71-77 are missing; pages 78-81, 108 are in manuscript. A memoir of Mrs. Spring's years with Marcus Spring and their literary and political friends. An interesting text, which expands on and explains much of the information contained in the letters, including a lengthy part on Spring's efforts on the behalf of John Brown, their travels with Margaret Fuller and friendships with Fredrika Bremer and Lydia Maria Child. (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Newspaper clippings about Rebecca Spring
  - 3 clippings of stories about Mrs. Spring from southern California newspapers, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Invitations
  - 3 ptd. cards, about 1867.(1) Marcus & Rebecca Spring's 25th wedding anniversary; (2) Chief Justice Chase (daughter's marriage); (3) Dinner invitation from George Washington. (Box 2, Folder 93)
- Photographs
  - Bernhard, Sarah. 1 photograph, s., 1906., Clarke, James Freeman. 1 photographic portrait.; Plympton, Eben. 1 photograph, s., 1883.American; (Shakespearean) actor. Supported Lillian Adelaide [?] eillson and Mary Anderson.; Rearney, J.L. 1 amateur snapshot, 1902.; Spring, Marcus. 1 cabinet photograph, ca. 1873 [?].; Spring, Rebecca. 1 photograph, Aug., 1901(avec `Bijou' and mon petit chat). (Box 2, Folder 94)
- Eagleswood Military Academy
  - 3 items. Engraved and printed prospectus for and catalogue for Five Years of... NY, 1866. (Box 2, Folder 95)
- Sketches
  - Two unsigned pencil sketches, one of a Charleston prison cell, dated Nov. 9, 1859;the other of Harper's Ferry, Nov. 9, 1859.See also R. Spring's typescript. (Box 2, Folder 96)